<ItacWorkItem RecordId="023-000002269" WorkId="000297"><ShortTitle>Alexandri Carerii Patavini Iuris Utriusque Doctoris Peripateticae Sacraeque Sapientiae studiosi </ShortTitle><LongTitle>De somnis deque Divinatione per somnia brevis Consideratio. Ad Reverendissimus Ascanium Marchesinum Episcopum Maiorensem Dominum et patronum colendiss[imum]</LongTitle><ItacAcademyItem AcademyId="0026" RecordID="021-000002259">Accademia degli Animosi</ItacAcademyItem><Format>4&#176;</Format><City CityId="3"><PublicationPlaceItalianName>Padova</PublicationPlaceItalianName><PublicationPlaceEnglishName>Padua</PublicationPlaceEnglishName><PublicationPlaceLatinName>Patavii</PublicationPlaceLatinName></City><PublicationYear>1575</PublicationYear><Shelfmark>719.g.37</Shelfmark><Subjects>Dreams|Philosophy|Aristotelianism|Hermeticism</Subjects><Language>Latin</Language><Pagination>pp. 15r-v</Pagination><Marginalia>No</Marginalia><Authors><ItacPersonItem PersonId="15726" RecordID="022-000002263">Carriero,Alessandro,,1546-1626</ItacPersonItem></Authors><Notes>According to Tomasini, `Elogia`, p. 363, Carriero delivered this lesson at the Accademia degli Animosi. This is confirmed in the Dedication. According to Olivieri Secchi, `Carriero, Alessandro`, in DBI, in this publication the author attempts a reconciliation between the Aristotelian interpretation of dreams, and theologians` teachings. Thus, dreams are sent to selected human beings by God, through nature. This went against Plato`s and Avicenna`s theory, according to which dreams are innate.</Notes><Censors><ItacPersonItem PersonId="15743" RecordID="022-000002286">Manentus Gabianus,Bonaventura,,</ItacPersonItem></Censors><CensorsAgreement>Fr. Bonaventura Manentus Gabianus Vic. Rever. P. Inquisitoris Paduae vidit et fidem facit nihil contineri contra fidem, contra principes aut contra bonos mores, et permittit impressioni dari.</CensorsAgreement><Dedicatees><ItacPersonItem PersonId="15736" RecordID="022-000002276">Marchesinus,Ascanius,Bishop,</ItacPersonItem></Dedicatees><Printers><ItacPersonItem PersonId="9635" RecordID="022-000001682">Pasquati,Lorenzo,,fl. 1561-1624</ItacPersonItem></Printers><PrinterOrnament>CNCE9514</PrinterOrnament><Citation>Lorenza Gianfrancesco and Simone Testa, directed by Jane Everson, Denis Reidy, Lisa Sampson, assisted by Thomas Denman, for the Italian Academies Database project.</Citation></ItacWorkItem>